Mercury Springberry

Location: Everett, WA, 98204

Email: mspringberry@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mercury-springberry-16286b198
Github: github.com/mercspring | Portfolio: mercspring.github.io/personal-portfolio/

Summary

A full-stack web developer with a broad base of technical skills and experience living and working all over the world.

Technical Skills

Front-End Skills: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript/ECMAscript 6, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap 4, Local

Storage, Cookies, Indexed DB, React.js

Back-End Skills: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Sessions, JS web tokens

Projects

Recipes by Nutrition

github.com/mercspring/recipes-by-nutrition | mercspring.github.io/recipes-by-nutrition/

An AJAX web application that allows users to search for recipes, view nutritional info for those recipes and save favorites. It is a Front-End only web app that utilizes jQuery for the DOM manipulation and the API calls. The recipes are pulled in from the Spoonacular recipe API and fed into the EDAMAM nutrition API for processing. Favorites are saved to local storage.

The Shark Quiz

github.com/mercspring/the-shark-guiz | mercspring.github.io/the-shark-guiz/

A quiz about sharks. Built using vanilla Javascript, HTML and CSS. Bootstrap is the only 3rd party library used, mostly for its mobile responsive grid system. Local Storage is used to create a leaderboard so users can keep track of their highscores.

The Social Petwork

https://github.com/sophia2798/social_petwork | https://secret-meadow-51163.herokuapp.com/

An app for finding friends for your dog. The app lets users create a profile for their dog and then search for other dogs in the same zip code as theirs. The app is built using the node.js, express, express-handlebars and MySQL on the back-end and jQuery and Materialize CSS on the front-end.

Indulge

https://github.com/sophia2798/social_petwork | https://secret-meadow-51163.herokuapp.com/

A MERN app for hiring recently out-of-work chefs to cook in consumers homes. The app has a fully mobile responsive front-end built in react and a back-end built with MongoDB and Express. The app allows chefs to create profiles to show-off their work experience and cooking. Users are able to search through these chefs to find a suitable candidate.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development - University of Washington Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering - Washington State University

Employment

iDevice Technician 2017-2019

IT Services Gold Coast Southport, QLD, AUS

• Inspected and troubleshooted problems associated with iPhones, iPads, Macbooks and PCs and provided repairs

- Explained technical topics to non-technical stakeholders
- Regularly investigated research topics to gain a more thorough understanding of unique issues in order to broaden my knowledge and better address customers needs

Worker 2017 - 2017

Hurford Wholesale Staypleton, QLD, AUS

• Ensured customers received quality hardwood flooring on time by stacking and sorting flooring efficiently

Temp Worker 2016 -2017P

Express Employment

Spokane, WA

- Canvased ten different neighbourhoods over the course of 3 weeks to help elect Cathy McMorris-Rogers for congress
- Surveyed hundreds of people over the phone about their thoughts on the local healthcare system while maintaining a polite and professional demeanour
- Demolished a large concrete patio with a sledge hammer in frigged -16°C weather

Holographic Technician

2016 - 2016

New Light Industries

Spokane, WA

- Worked independently to design and build a spin developer to automate the process of developing photo-resist plates. Programmed the controls for the valves and stepper-motor driven pumps using C, fabricated chassis's for the touch screen, stepper motor control board, and power supply on a mill and performed all necessary plumbing, wiring and soldering
- Performed the company's first full cycle production of a roll of 1000 holographic security labels including: nickel shim creation, embossing, serialisation, adhesive application and die cutting
- Led research into the creation of break-patterns using UV curable resin for the company's holographic labels performing numerous tests into how the different UV resins behaved when cured on top of one another

Lot Checker and Valet 2014 - 2015

Diamond Parking Spokane, WA

- Enforced parking violations in over 30 different car parks while collecting payments
- Parked cars in a small parking garage for the tenants and customers of a downtown building

Electrical Engineering Intern

2012 - 2012

Schweitzer Engineering Laboratories

Pullman, WA

- Customised a linux kernel for an AM1808 ARM microprocessor using the Sitara Linux SDK
- Designed a power system to convert a 12V rail down to a 5V and 3.3V rail using PSpice and Webench software tools
- Tested possible replacement parts for power relays to ensure the company had a fall back part if the current part was discontinued. Analysed data sheets to find suitable replacements, soldered new parts into power relays to ensure they worked properly, wrote a report on my tests and recommendations